#### Contact

mnvikingsr1@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/robmyers-35b51463 (LinkedIn) github.com/ROBMYERS1856/ University-of-Minnesota- (Personal)

### Top Skills

Strategic Planning
Emergency Management
Leadership

Certifications
CompTIA Security+

# Rob Myers

I am currently looking for the opportunity to expand my career. I am looking for new opportunities in the Cyber Security field.

**United States** 

# Summary

I have a diverse back ground spanning over 20 years in leadership, supervisory and

management positions. I have a back ground in fields such as Security, Operations and Program

Management, Manufacturing, and Warehousing. I have a proven work ethic, positive

attitude, and abilities to contribute to the over all success of the organization. I am now

looking for the opportunity to expand my career into new opportunities in the Cyber

Security field. I have recently graduated from the University of Minnesota Cyber Security

Boot Camp as well as successfully passed the CompTIA Security Plus Certification.

I am familiar with Linux, Windows, and Azure systems with ability to create scripts in Bash and Powershell. Also familiar with Burp and Wireshark, Network organization skills and diagram creation. Actively looking for the right role to deliver value with potential for growth.

University of Minnesota:

Networking:

Packet Analysis

Wireshark

Systems:

Windows and Linux Administration Techniques Windows and Linux Hardening

Cybersecurity:

Secure Network Design and Architecture Risk Management

Cryptography
Vulnerability Assessment
Identity and Access Management
Cloud Security

Ethical Hacking and Penetration:

Kali Linux

Metasploit

Hashcat

**Burp Suite** 

Web Vulnerabilities and Security

Cybersecurity Careers:

Digital Forensics Methods

Penetration Testing

Vulnerability Assessment

Security Operations and Analytics

Programming and Scripting:

**Bash Scripting** 

PowerShell Scripting

# Experience

PAE

Supply and Inventory Warehouse Supervisor February 2020 - Present (1 year 9 months)

Lakeville, Minnesota, United States

- # Conduct cross training, promote a team environment and continual improvement processes. Ensure all employees can perform efficiently and safely in all functions
- # Perform forklift training/certification/review forklift daily safety check off sheets
- # Ensure customer orders are completed correctly and in a timely manner
- # Perform product cycle counts (inventory control), maintain site inventory accuracy, and grid inventory of finished goods
- # Assist with warehouse safety audits and inspections
- # Ensure warehouse is in a safe, organized, and sanitary condition. Ensure that all equipment is in good operating condition

- # Review and verify that all product moving to the warehouse have the correct product description, quantity, and lot number (Label Verification)
- # Review and follow all safety guidelines, workplace safety policies and OSHA requirements with personnel
- # Assist with personnel issues (i.e., disciplinary actions, promotions, evaluations, and interviews)
- # Ensure all received unprocessed product is processed, labeled correctly, inventoried, and stored appropriately
- # Operate the United States Postal Service computer system: Mail Transport Equipment System (MTESS)
- # Supervise receiving and dispatch to include but not limited to trailer arrival, dispatch, bill of ladings, inventory tracking, trailer moves to and from the yard, loading and unloading of trailers and other primary functions
- # Verify employee timecards daily, approve and submit weekly

#### Hormel Foods

Production Area Supervisor (Ready to Eat/Raw) June 2019 - January 2020 (8 months)

Austin, Minnesota, United States

- # Lead team members by managing and executing plant processes, goals, standards, and objectives
- # Manages team members in attaining production goals and quality standards.
- # Present monthly safety and food quality training to employees
- # Develop and train staff to promote talent growth and accomplish work safely and efficiently
- # Ensures appropriate resources (including materials, raw materials, PPE, equipment, and staffing needs) are available to maintain production schedule # Perform weekly new hire evaluations
- # Supervise sanitation procedures and standards for the Bacon Processing Area (Bacon Bits, Smoke House, Pickle Room, Tumblers, and Injectors)
- # Supports continuous improvement processes to ensure that goals in safety, quality, cost, and customer service are met
- # Monitor production inventories to ensure accuracy and achieve production goals and cost saving measures
- # Responsible for achieving daily production goals and performance standards. Ensure appropriate records (quality control documentation) are maintained and documented accurately.
- # Ensure appraisals, discipline, and personnel matters within the group are timely and properly dispositioned as well as adhering to all Collective Bargaining Agreement stipulations

# Work independently to complete daily activities according to work schedule.

### Cargill

Production Area Supervisor December 2014 - May 2019 (4 years 6 months)

Albert Lea, Minnesota, United States

# As the Production Area Supervisor, daily operational responsibilities include approving employee timecards, plan and assign work based on the daily production schedule, attain production and quality goals while ensuring a safe working environment. Critical requirement is to meet all USDA/ OSHA standards and regulations as well as following the Collective Bargaining Agreement

# Other primary responsibilities include the following: performing sanitation audits to include reviewing Safety Data Sheets (SDS), employee safety observations, facility inspections, Quality Control inspections (PRE-OP), and submit all appropriate work orders and other documentation is accurate in order to meet customer and quality requirements

- # Complete all action plans, and Plant Inspections as assigned
  # Other responsibilities include conduct monthly engagement meetings with
  employees, perform employee evaluations, address behavior issues by
  providing coaching, verbal warnings, and progressive discipline
  # Conduct facility tours for contractors, visitors, corporate employees, and
  customers
- # Facilitate new employee trainings
- # Demonstrate a strong understanding of food manufacturing and good manufacturing practices (GMP's) for all areas in the Plant (Raw Side, Ready to Eat, including sanitation practices)

#### PAE

Program Manager and Training Coordinator April 2011 - April 2014 (3 years 1 month)

Afghanistan

Served as the program primary point of contact to the Ministry of Justice (MOJ) and the Juvenile Rehabilitation Directorate (JRD) to improve operational practices and procedures nationwide for 33 provincial Juvenile Detention Centers

Provided oversight on several facility improvement and humanitarian projects at local JRC Facilities throughout Afghanistan to include new construction/remodel projects, sanitation and septic removal

Successfully created and implemented the Pre-Employment Training (PET). The PET training consisted of 160-hour training course covering 31 security topics.

Successfully created and implemented the Executive Leadership Course (ELC) training (80-hour training course) for Juvenile Rehabilitation Directorate (JRD) Directors, JRC Facility Directors and Provincial Justice Directors from all 33 provinces.

Successfully hosted the JRD Directors Conference. Primary responsibilities included conducting security background checks on all participants, arranging travel, lodging, food services, and submitting for and the distribution of per diem money and travel expenses

Successfully created and implemented Operational Directives/Policies and Administrative Rules for the JRD/MOJ at all 33 locations nationwide. Primary goal was to implement consistent operational and management practices utilizing the Operational Directives/Policies and Administrative Rules we successfully created for long term viability and program success Submit purchase requests, coordinate deliveries, and manage all appropriate documentation

Create vender contracts/Scope of Work (SOW) agreements for subcontracted vendors to support humanitarian efforts, and established Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs) within the Capacity Team's Juvenile component Compile reports on searches, contraband, population counts, classification reports, Cost reports, PER Stat reports, quarterly reports, monthly data collection, and weekly mentoring activities

Oregon Department of Corrections Operations Shift Supervisor June 2002 - April 2011 (8 years 11 months) Salem, Oregon, United States

- # Maintain the safety and security of the facility and respond to all emergencies while supervising all staff and inmates. Also responsible for covering the Officer In-Charge (OIC) responsibilities in their absence.
- # Perform security related duties to include the following: supervising housing units, and security staff, conducting searches, perimeter security, and supervising sensitive and secure areas such as Master Control and Disciplinary Housing Units.
- # Armed Post qualified
- # Work with community organizations that provide services to Inmates as well as interact and visitors when supervising visitation.
- # Review and update facility post orders

# Review and follow all Dept. Policies and Procedures as well as Administrative Rules

# Field Training Officer (FTO): duties included training new employees on all emergency procedures, administrative rules, policies, procedures, post orders, and basic correctional objectives as well as submitting all new employee reviews/evaluations, and reports to the FTO Supervisor. Also administered all training material, tests and facilitated/presented classroom training sessions. # Have experience through the Departments Succession Plan Program job shadowing the Public Information Officer (PIO). This included conducting oncamera interviews and facilitating tours to media representatives. # Security Threat Group Investigator/ Team Leader (STG).

## Education

University of Minnesota Boot Camps

Cyber Security · (June 2021 - December 2021)

University of Minnesota Boot Camps CompTIA Security Plus

University of South Dakota

Bachelor of Science, Mass Communications/Public Relations · (1998 - 2002)

University of South Dakota

Bachelor of Science - BS, Contemporary Media and Journalism (MASS Communications) · (August 1998 - May 2002)